Hello.
In this lecture, we're going to go over how to create a pause menu to get started.
Open up the Widget Blueprint folder.
Right click and go User Interface Widget Blueprint.
Cool this.
Ah.
Pause menu.
Once you've done this.
Open it up and go over to the palette and search for a canvas panel.
Direct us into our designer.
Then look for an image.
Drag this image into our canvass panel and just going to anchor and select this one, which will anchor
it across the whole of the screen.
And under offset, put zero in all the values.
Once you've done this, change the Z order of this to be minus one.
This will place the image behind anything that we put on top of it.
And if we go to color and opacity, change this to be black.
And change the alpha value to be something like 0.6.
That works well.
Then go.
Okay.
We're now ready to set up our pause menu.
If we go to the palette and look for a vertical box, track this in and place this in the center of
our screen.
Also, make sure to anchor this in the center of our screen.
Then look for a button.
And drag two buttons onto the vertical box.
Next, look for some text and drag one text on top of each button.
Select the first text and make it say resume.
We'll make it so that when we click this button and we pause our game, clicking this button will resume
our game and select the second text and make this a main menu.
We'll make it to that when the player clicks upon.
It will take them to the main menu, select the first button and just go to padding and add a padding
or 50 just so that there's a bit of a gap between them.
Then I'm going to select both text.
They're a bit small, so I'm going to make them a size 50.
Then if we go to our pilot dragon the text and anchor it to the top and make this a paused.
And I'm just going to increase the size of this to 100.
We can compile and save this.
So we're going to make sure that when we press a certain key in our game, it will open up its menu
and pause our game.
If we close this and go to edit and go to product settings, scroll down and look for input and go add
new action.
Mapping.
Call this or pause.
And for the key, I'm going to make it.
When I press the button, it will pull the game.
So scroll down and select the weapon.
We can now close this and go to all play a character blueprint.
And in some free space, right click and look for pause.
And so this one that we just made action event pause.
When we press this button, we're going to drag a fit and we'll create widget.
The widget we're going to create is going to be the pause menu that we just made.
Then we're going to add this to our viewport.
Now in order to make Apple's menu actually work, Let's go back to our pause menu and go to the graph.
A bank construct.
This will happen as soon as our pause menu is shown on our screen.
We're going to drive up here and look for set game paused.
Make sure to check this and this will just make it so our game is paused.
After we do this to make sure our player character can click on any one of these buttons, we're going
to right click and not forget player controller and drag up here and look for set show, mouse cursor.
And just make sure this is checked.
This will make it so we can see our mouse cursor.
Then if we drag off here and look for set input UI only.
And this will just make it so our controller is compatible with our main menu.
So this is what's going to happen when we open up our pause menu.
We're going to pause our game and then chew our mouse cursor.
Next, if we go back to the designer and select the resume button.
Scroll down and go unclipped.
When we click on this button, we're going to unpause and resume our game.
So if we drag off here and look for set game paused and just make sure this is unchecked, the next
thing we're going to do is hide our mouse cursor.
So I'm just going to copy this.
And if we drag off here and across that show mouse cursor and just leave this unchecked, then we need
to tell the player controller to go back into game mode so that we automatically possess our player
character.
So if we drive off here and look for a set input game only.
And then we need to make sure that our pause menu is no longer on the screen.
To do that, we can just drag off here and look for the remove from parent node.
This will make it to our pause menu.
It's removed from our screen.
If we go back to the designer and select the main menu and scroll down and go unclipped.
When we click this button, we are going to open our main menu level.
So go open level by name.
Then type in whatever you call your main menu level.
So I.
My main menu map.
And now we're going to compile.
We can test this all out.
So if I go play, I'm in my level one.
If I press the people that will show me my post screen, I can go resume and my menu.
If I click resume, it will resume my game and I can play it again.
If I press the menu again and go me menu, it will take me to my main menu.
So with this, we've created a pause menu.